Ásgeir Berg Matthíasson

asgeirberg@hi.is https://asgeirberg.org

Research interests

I currently run my own research project to develop a conventionalist account of mathematical truth, funded by the *Icelandic Research Fund* (RANNÍS). It is based on my previous work on the rule-following paradox and the philosophy of mathematics.

As a part of this work, I'm also writing papers on inference, what it is to follow a rule, as well as semantic dispositionalism.

Areas of Specialisation: Philosophy of language, philosophy of mathematics, logic, Wittgenstein, the rule-following paradox

Areas of Competence: Metaphysics, epistemology, history of analytic philosophy.

Current position

2022 — present Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Institute of Philosophy, University of Iceland

Previous positions

2021 — 2022 Adjunct Lecturer

University of Iceland

2020 — 2021 Sessional Instructor University of Iceland

2016 — 2019 Early Stage Researcher

University of Stirling

Education

2020 **PhD in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

2015 **M.Litt. in Philosophy**, University of St Andrews and University of Stirling (SASP)

2013 M.Sc. in Logic, University of Amsterdam

2011 BA in Philosophy and Ancient Greek, University of Iceland